# Samantha Pendleton BSc

## IT GRADUATE | DATA SCIENTIST

ABERYSTWYTH, SY23 samanfapendle@outlook.com



github.com/sap218



twitter.com/sap218

## **PROFILE**

Currently studying my postgraduate degree in Data Science after completing my undergraduate degree in IT. I have an extensive set of skills, ranging from data science applications, IT, business and communications. I am an organised individual, who works well with colleagues especially through fast-paced environments. I have strong experience in assisting people through my employment and education.

## **SKILLS**

#### **DATA SCIENCE**

Bioinformatics, Statistics (modelling), Machine Learning, Data Mining

#### **BUSINESS & COMMUNICATION**

System Analysist, Business Planning, Presentations: slideshows & posters

#### **LANGUAGES**

Python & R; HTML, CSS, & PHP; SQL: PostgreSQL, SQLite, & NoSQL;

IT

Administration, Operating Systems Cyber Security, Various Software

## **PROJECTS**

» Postgraduate Dissertation Masters project 2018

Project title: TBD

In fulfilment of the Postgraduate Degree; IMPACS & IBERs department at Aberystwyth University

» Bioinformatics Research 2017

An Analysis of current software for nanopore metagenomic data Computer Science and IBERs department at Aberystwyth University

Available: http://github.com/sap218/misc

### **EDUCATION**

» MSc (Masters) candidate in Computer Science 2017-2018

**Data Science** at Aberystwyth University

Additional: Advisor/Demonstrator, President of Computer Science Society

» BSc (Bachelors) graduate in Computer Science 2014-2017

2:1 Business Information Technology at Aberystwyth University

Dissertation: Web Major Project: The Little Cake Box Website

In fulfilment of the Bachelor's Degree; Computer Science at Aberystwyth University

Available: <a href="http://users.aber.ac.uk/sap21/">http://users.aber.ac.uk/sap21/</a>

Additional: Demonstrator, Peer Mentor

» A-levels 2012-2014

IT (D\*D\*), Home Economics [Health & Social Care] (M)

Advanced Subsidiary: Mathematics & German

Extra-Curricular: Art

#### **EXPERIENCE**

» Researcher, Bioinformatics; Aberystwyth University 2017

Project: "An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data"

» Student Worker; AberWorks, Aberystwyth University 2016+

Jobs: Demonstrator/Advisor, Summer Operative: Ambassador

» Assistant; Information Services at Hugh Owen Library, Aberystwyth University 2016-2017

Jobs: Assisted staff, attended focus groups, made strategy & floor plans

» Classroom Assistant; Rimrose Hope Primary School 2011

Jobs: Helped plus guided pupils

» Volunteering/Charity Work; educational environments 2006-2017

Jobs: Environmental work, assisted with charity events, aiding the elderly

Peer mentor for the Computer Science Department

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

» BCS Lovelace Colloquium attendee 2017 – 2018

- An Analysis of current software for nanopore metagenomic data 2018
- The best user interface designs for the simplest of websites; making sites attractive 2017 Poster Presentation at Women's Conference Aberystwyth University/Sheffield University
- » Manual Handling Course 2016, 2017

Certificate from Aberystwyth University

» Diversity Certificate 2016+

Diversity in the workplace training from Aberystwyth University

» Work Shadowing Volunteer 2016

Peer Mentor participation at Aberystwyth University Careers Service Volunteer Work Placement

#### **INTERESTS**

I enjoy a wide variety of activities; I appreciate cinematography, reading small fictional novels, and music. I am keen on puzzles; involving video games plus chess. Most of my time is spent on personal projects: I am keen on developing my knowledge in my spare time through web browsing. Personal projects can be found here: <a href="https://github.com/sap218">https://github.com/sap218</a> including my personal site with blogs about projects can be found here: <a href="https://sap218.github.io/">https://sap218.github.io/</a>.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

"An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data" Samantha C Pendleton

bioRxiv 288969; doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/288969

Note: This article is a preprint and has not been peer-reviewed